# **Darasy Reth**

reth.d@husky.neu.edu darasy.github.io www.linkedin.com/in/darasyreth www.github.com/darasy

### Summary

Computer systems engineering - IoT graduate student and experienced software developer with an understanding of general software development, algorithms, machine learning, and artificial intelligence. Experienced and skilled at working in a team, highly responsible and hard working. Interested in a software development position utilizing Python, C, Java, and R as well as applying data science and machine learning knowledge.

### Technical skills

Programming languages: Python, Java, C, C++, R, SML

Operating systems: Linux, Macintosh, Windows 7/8/10

Web technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Database: MySQL

### **Education**

# Northeastern University, Boston, MA

Master of Science in Computer Systems Engineering - IoT

**Expected December 2020** 

Relevant courses: Data Science Engineering Method and Tools, Concepts of Object-Oriented Design

### State University of New York at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

December 2018

Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics

Relevant courses: Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Algorithm Design and Analysis, Software Engineering

- Dean's List.
- Tau Sigma National Honor Society.
- Undergraduate research assistant at the Embedded Sensing and Computing (ESC) lab.
- Undergraduate student under experimental learning program at Curbell Medical.

# **Experience**

# **Experiential Learning Project, Curbell Medical**, Buffalo, NY **Software Developer and Researcher**

August 2018 – December 2018

Project: "Characterizing Human Movement Using a Wearable Device"

- Designed machine learning models to analyze unusual patient's movements using K-Nearest Neighbors, Random Forest, and Convolutional Neural Networks.
- Collected patient's movements dataset using Arduino to feed to the models.

# Embedded Sensing and Computing Lab, Buffalo, NY

May 2018 – December 2018

# **Undergraduate Research Assistant**

### **Lead Software Developer and Researcher**

Project: "A Deep Learning Fall Detection Method in Elderly Home Exercise Programs"

- Built a tool to extract human body key points from video surveillance using a deep learning approach.
- Designed a deep learning model to identify and to distinguish fall motion from other human activities.

### **Software Developer and Researcher**

Project: "BigFoot: A Mobile Solution toward Foot Parameters Extraction"

- Utilized computer vision technology to analyze human foot key points using OpenCV library.
- Designed algorithms to determine the foot shape of a person using Euclidean distance, circle, and ellipse circumference.

# Academic Projects, State University of New York at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY

Spectacle Detection

August 2017 - December 2017

Built Hidden Markov Model and Artificial Neural Network classifiers to identify if people wear glasses.